SENIOR PROJECT MANAGER

Professional Summary

Technical project manager with 20 years' experience with delivering large-scale infrastructure and application solutions in telecommunications, educational, and e-commerce sectors. Experienced in leading cross-functional business and technical teams from inception to completion using analytical, organization, communication, and team building skills. Fluent in waterfall and Agile planning and delivery methodologies.

Licenses

Project Management - PMBOK knowledge, process, and practices. SDLC: Waterfall, Agile, and Scrum methodologies. Administrator level use of JIRA and Confluence. Expert level use of MS Project. Process Development and Management - Workflow creation and documentation. Expert level use of Visio. Administrator level use of ServiceNow.

Professional Experience

Senior Project Manager 03/2015 to Current

Kitchell Livermore, CA

- DevOps automation standardization Led the inception and execution of the standardization of GapTech's Chef platform and base
 configurations with the goals of mitigating technical debt, aligning infrastructure deployments between stores, e-commerce, and corporate
 systems, and advancing configuration management with new features.
- Collected requirements and drove the architecture design, development, and deployment of an enterprise scale Chef server.
- This was a consolidation of different versioned Chef servers.
- Coordinated the testing and upgrade of Chef client and migration of environments (development to production across 3 data centers) to new management server.
- The effort required the participation of 30+ product, development, operation, and release engineering teams.
- Migrated 30,000+ nodes while maintaining stability for testing pipelines and release schedules.
- Tested and introduced new Analytics feature to capture and visualize previously unavailable metrics for performance of nodes.
- Enterprise logging deployment Managed the deployment of the standardized enterprise logging solution (Splunk) for GapTech.
- Collected requirements, led design, and deployment of data center forwarders, clustered indexers, and clustered search heads across 10,000 + nodes and endpoints.
- Planned and managed the ingestion of logs into archive or indexed modes for Operations to be able to create alerts, search data, and create reports.
- Planned and managed the ingestion of InfoSec logs from firewalls, switches, and security applications.
- Coordinated testing between InfoSec and Splunk security apps and add ons.

IT Project Manager and ScrumMaster 03/2011 to 03/2015

Alleare Consulting Other South Georgia, GA

- DevOps automation transformation for operations Designed, planned, and managed the deployment and adoption of Chef configuration
 management for operations stability which led to process change for server builds from template and manual deployment to code
 development and release workflow.
- Designed and implemented training for 20 operations engineers on Chef domain-specific language, requirements writing, test writing, code review, and Agile/Scrum practices.
- This effort consisted of developing and releasing 40 new cookbooks, deploying 4000+ nodes, testing and migrating 250+ applications, and coordinating activities between 20+ development and production support teams over the course of 14 months.
- Configuration management decreased operation tickets filed by 30% and reduced MTTR by 15%.
- DevOps automation transformation for continuous integration Designed, introduced, and integrated Chef into a continuous integration pipeline for e-commerce backend services development.
- The service provided Chef, vCloud, and Jenkins for development and release teams to automate, standardize, and manage deployments.
- These teams were able to reduce environment deployment from 2 weeks to 1 day by deploying multiple base images and builds from cookbooks.
- Aligned test framework to include infrastructure and application in the same test suite.
- This included change in process, test suites, and convergence of testing applications.
- Managed the consolidation of application code and cookbooks from Git, Gerrit, and SVN repositories into a single GitLab instance.
- Collaboration tools product manager Product Manager of the macys.com JIRA instance.
- The instance supported 100+ projects, 2000+ users, and 200,000+ stories, tasks, and issues.
- Met regularly with the user community (product owners, ScrumMasters, and engineering leads) to configure projects to suit their requirements while aligning to best Agile practices.
- Product Manager of macys.com Confluence instance.
- The instance supported 75+ spaces, 4000+ users, and 30,000 pages.
- Provided guidance to the user community how to best leverage Confluence features to articulate, document, track, and work together on ideas within and across teams.
- Maintained roadmap for architecture, version upgrades, plugins, and interoperability with macys.com tools.
- Email assembly application development Led the inception and development of macys.com first email assembly application that allowed macys.com to customize emails marketing campaigns.
- Managed stories and tasks using Agile methodology as ScrumMaster.
- Led a team of developers, quality engineers, and data architects to deliver a proof of concept release that scaled up to a clustered application over the course of 24 months.
- Deliverables included application development, database implementation, interoperability testing between CRM database and email vendors, and continued hardware testing as application scaled up.

- Big data transformation Led the inception and conversion of macys.com's OLTP database into a mixed workload OLAP database to support macys.com marketing analytics initiatives.
- Managed stories and tasks using Agile methodology as ScrumMaster.
- Conducted standups, backlog grooming, sprint planning, retrospectives, and removed blockers by working within teams and cross-functionally.
- Calculated and reported velocity, burn up, budget and status to management.
- Worked with financial analysts, marketing analytics users, data architects, and hardware architects to define requirements and create a plan to migrate the data while maintaining production SLAs.
- Completed migrating and restructuring the database over the course of 12 months.
- Deliverables included hardware migration, database creation, data transformation (cubing) and loading, testing and migration of batch jobs, and conducting interoperability, acceptance, and performance testing.

Program Manager 06/2009 to 12/2009

Kitchell San Francisco, CA

- Educational WLAN deployment for New South Wales, Australia Recruited specifically to manage the Australian Department of Education and Training (DET) deployment, which was Aruba's largest deal to date (\$17M).
- WLAN scope of work included 463 education sites and 20 data centers covering the New South Wales region.
- Created program dashboard that reported all deployment issues and forecasts.
- Held regular meetings with executive management to report status and communicate issues between customer, partners, and impacted business units.
- Managed action items with senior management in hardware engineering, software engineering, QE, and product management to ensure complete solution delivery as specified by the RFP terms.
- Managed milestones for production code release.
- Worked with engineering team to triage and resolve observed deviations from regression testing during deployment to produce appropriate issue reports, bug fixes, and feature requests.
- Coordinated hardware deliverables between senior management in supply chain operations and the integration partners to ensure timely and proper product delivery.
- Managed the integration of the Aruba controller and WLAN equipment and AirWave management product into DET's multi-vendor support model.
- Drove standardization of process and documents for DET's newly formed support group.

Senior Project Manager 07/2005 to 07/2008

Wayfair Llc Seattle, WA

- Professional services project management Managed project life cycle for domestic and international implementations of Veraz's VoIP software and hardware platform.
- Responsibilities included gathering requirements, network design, issuing statement of work, creating project plan, custom feature development, software and hardware deployment, systems integration, acceptance testing, and operational transition.
- Project sizes ranged between \$8M to \$15M.
- Session border controller software development Managed the concurrent development of Veraz's security (SBC) and QoS software solution utilizing Stage-gate NPI methodology.
- Directed the integration of these products into existing customers' systems on a pre-beta basis.
- Conducted the field trials and worked cross functionally with product management, engineering, and QA to drive refinement of features to finalize the GA offering.
- SIP-I protocol handling software development Managed the design, development, and testing of Veraz SIP-I software used for proof of concept testing.
- Completed successful IPX (IP eXchange) trial between Telecom New Zealand and Telekom Austria.
- Trial tested interoperability of Veraz's alpha release to process SIP-I protocol packets from Telekom Austria and complete IMS based calls on the Telecom New Zealand Mobile network.
- Coordinated activities between teams from each company across four continents.

Senior Manager 07/2004 to 06/2005

AirSurf Wireless City, STATE

- Useability and scalabilty proof of concept pilots.
- Planned and managed two greenfield controller-based WLAN infrastructure deployment pilots.
- Activities included developing project plans, managing resources, RF site survey, procurement, structured cabling, access point and antenna
 installation and configuration, controller configuration, and RADIUS server configuration.
- The pilots demonstrated proof of concept for security and usability of a single, partitioned 802.11 a/b/g network in multi-tenant commercial environment.

Education and Training

B.A: Economics University of California at Berkeley Economics

Project Management Professional PMP (1392223) - Project Management Institute ITIL V3 Foundations - AXELOS Skills

DevOps - Intermediate knowledge of Chef configuration management tool. Intermediate level of use in Linux (Red Hat and Ubuntu) and Solaris. Working knowledge of Git/SVN. Working knowledge of Jenkins. Infrastructure -X86 based platforms. Server virtualization (VMware and Hyper-V). SAN technology. Cisco Systems routing/switching products. Sun SPARC platforms. Hosted computing (AWS and Rackspace) Data Communications -WAN technologies (ATM, MPLS, Optical technologies). TCP/IP architecture. Enterprise WLAN networking (IEEE 802.11). VoIP and IMS technology. Programming languages - Basic level of coding. Java (J2EE), Ruby, Chef DSL, PHP, HTML, xHTML, and CSS.